Thaddeus W. Maliszewski collection CPAA 86.04
Connecticut Polish American Archives, Elihu Burritt Library, Central Connecticut State University
Thaddeus W. Maliszewski collection
1935-2004
CPAA 86.04
Connecticut Polish American Archives
14.5 Linear feet
Thaddeus W. Maliszewski a lawyer, military officer, civic leader, was born in Hartford in 1922 and died in 2009. Graduate of Hillyer Junior College (Hartford), Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.) and University of Connecticut Law School. During WWII he served in the Pacific, was a member of the National Guard and Governor's Military Staff, finished his military career in the rank of Brigadier General. He served as a judge for several courts, was very active in the Democratic Party. For many years served in different positions in the Polish American Congress on state and national level. In addition, Maliszewski was active in veterans' organizations, Polish American cultural organizations as well as in political organizations. The collection consists of his personal and professional papers along with information about Poland and Polish American culture.
Maliszewski, Thaddeus W.
Arrangement note
Material in this collection is arranged by series and within each series by date.
Biographical/Historical note
Thaddeus Walenty Maliszewski, referred to as “Ted” by most, was born on January 22, 1922 in Hartford, CT to Joseph Maliszewski and Apolonia Hajdasz as one of thirteen children. He attended Polish parochial school SS. Cyril & Methodius and then went on to Burr Jr. High, Bulkeley High, Hillyer Jr. College, West Virginia Wesleyan, Wesleyan University, and the University of Connecticut School of Law. During his schooling he was involved in several organizations, serving as a leader in most of them on top of his achievements in the National Honors Society and Student Council. He was a member of Troop 41 and served as Patrol Leader, Assistant Scoutmaster and Eagle Scout. He served in the army during WWII in the South Pacific Theatre and received an honorable discharge as a Sergeant in 1946. He was commissioned a 2nd Lieutenant in 1949 and promoted to Colonel in the CT National Guard. In 1951 he married Barbara Karpienia and they had six children. Maliszewski practiced law since 1950 in a private law office, the Windsor court system, and in the Judge Advocate Corps of the Connecticut National Guard. He retired from the army in 1967 after 21 years of service. Maliszewski was very involved in Polonia by holding positions in organizations, participating in activities for the rights of Polish Americans, such as anti-defamation campaigns, and publishing his writing. He was a member of several organizations, notably the Polish American Congress, where he was active on national and state level, the American Council of Polish Cultural Clubs (ACPCC, later called the American Council of Polish Culture or ACPC), and Polish Legion of American Veterans (PLAV). In the PLAV he was vice-commander for Zone 1 (New England, New York and New Jersey) and in the PAC he was a National Director and the Connecticut district president. He also participated heavily in Democratic Party activities and campaigning on a local, state, and federal level in addition to serving as Windsor Town Chairman for many time. After retirement he and Barbara moved to Florida where he was a member of The Polish Cultural Society of Palm Beaches (PCSPB) and The Pulaski Legion of American-Polish Veterans and Auxiliary of Lake Worth, Inc. Thaddeus W. Maliszewski died on September 14, 2009 and is burried at the Cedar Hill Cemetery in Hartford.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The material in the collection was donated by Thaddeus W. Maliszewski in 1986. There were several later donations which included materials on the same time period as well as the newer material. Last donation was made by Mr. Maliszewski in July of 2009.
Scope and Contents note
This collection consists of personal and professional papers of Thaddeus W. Maliszewski (notated as TWM in finding aid). There are personal correspondence, official documents, reports, photographs, newspaper clippings and pamphlets relating to his life, organizations he participated in, politics, and his career practicing law. Some organizations include the American Council of Polish Cultural Clubs (ACPCC), Polish Legion of American Veterans (PLAV), Polish American Congress (PAC), The Polish Cultural Society of Palm Beaches (PCSPB), The Pulaski Legion of American-Polish Veterans and Auxiliary of Lake Worth, Inc. and others. Included is also plentiful information about Poland, Polish culture, and Polish- American life in Connecticut and throughout the country. The collection spans from approximately 1935 to 2004.
Related Archival Materials note
For related material go to the following collections: Polish Cultural Club of Greater Hartford records (CPAA 86-30) American Council for Polish Culture Collection (CPAA 96-03) Joseph L. Zazyczny collection of American Council for Polish Culture records CPAA 99-15
Conditions Governing Access note
The collection is open for research.
American Council of Polish Cultural Clubs; Democratic Party (Conn.); Poland -- History; Poland -- History -- 20th century; Polish American Congress; Polish Americans -- Connecticut -- Hartford -- History; Polish Americans -- Connecticut -- Politics and government; Polish Americans -- Correspondence; Polish Americans Societies, etc.; Polish Legion of American Veterans; Pulaski Day -- Periodicals; Pułaski, Kazimierz, 1747-1779
- Personal
  - Boy Scouts, Flying Eagle Patrol, Troop 41- Papers, correspondence, stories related to, Hartford., 1936-1938 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Polish Youth Day- Program and stories, Middletown, Connecticut., 1938 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Petition for the inclusion of the Polish language in the curriculum of The Bulkeley High School, Hartford., 1939 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence- Jean Urbanowicz - TWM., 1940-1942 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence- Polish Roman Catholic Union of America - TWM [college loan]., 1940-1955 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence- Peg Fitzgerald, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence- Helen Turczynski - TMW., 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Income, 1941-1942 and 1946-1952, 1941-1952 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Publishers, letters from - TWM; Nine poems by TWM, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Hillyer College, 1942; Hillyer College Alumni Association, 1950-1951, 1942-1951 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - State of Connecticut Tax Department, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence- Rosenblatt, Donald C.- TWM., 1942-1956 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence- Gertrude C. Walton- TWM., 1942 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence- Gertrude C. Walton- TWM, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence- Gertrude C. Walton- TWM., 1944 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - West Virginia Wesleyan College- Correspondence, ID, tests, clippings, 1942-1946 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence- Richard G. Cabbott- TWM., 1947-1954 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - TWM- Wesleyan Univiversity, B.A. diploma., 1947 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Wesleyan University, Middletown, Connecticut- Resume., 1946-1948 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence- Sprague, Jim & Ellen., 1947 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - University of Connecticut, School of Law- Correspondence, programs, 1945-1950. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - State Bar examination., 1948-1950 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Hartford Veteran's Council., 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Veterans Housing Council of Connecticut- Clippings, correspondence., 1948 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence- M[elanie] Lopata - TWM., 1949 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence- Adolph Freedman., 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence- Barbara Karpienia - TWM., 1950 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence- McCormick, Thomas., 1953-1957 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence- Sadlak, Antoni., 1949-1957 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence- Rudolph J. Daley., 1965 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - "All-American and mighty proud of that Polish name!" by Thaddeus W. Maliszewski., 1988 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Records of purchasing a property in Windsor., 1953 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - CCSU Polish Heritage Collection donation by TWM., 1975 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - TWM consultant to US State Deppartment For cultural exchange, correspondence., 1965 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Letters of recommendation by TWM., 1969-1978 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - TWM - Miscellaneous correspondence., 1968-1976 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Miscellaneous official correspondence., 1940-1958 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Miscellaneous personal correspondence., 1938-1953 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Miscellaneous documents., 1940-1987 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Scrap Book– News clippings from American and Polish American newspapers., 1935-1939 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Polish tradition- Newspaper clipping pictures, 1941. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Polish people- “Character of the Poles,” from Who are the Slavs?, 1919; Polish proverbs; newspaper clippings. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Poland- General information- Front page of “Nowy Swiat,” 1939; brochures, 1938., 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Polish music- “Polish Music” by Karl Stromenger; Newspaper clippings, 1941-1942. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Maps of Poland., 1937-1939 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Polish language- Alphabet, 1941; “The Polish Language”; newspaper clippings, 1939., 1939-1941 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Poland - “Report on the Poles”; newspaper clippings, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Polish literature- Newspaper clippings., 1941 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Kosciuszko- “Polish Patriot” cartoon; articles, 1946? (200th anniversary of birth) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Krakow- Clippings, 1939; “Poland, Land of the White Eagle” by Melville Bell Grosvenor; brochure, 1937., 1937-1939 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Poland- History- Articles; TWM handwritten notes., 1939-1941 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Poland- War pictures; Clippings, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Julian Niemcewicz- School work by TWM, 1935. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Poland- Government- Handwritten notes and article, 1938-1939. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Gdynia- Brochures; clippings, 1937-1939 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Famous Poles- Clippings; Polish Legion of American Veterans correspondence., 1939-1953 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Art in Poland- Clippings; “The Art of Poland Before the Partitions”; “Modern Polish Art.”, 1939-1941 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Polish Army and Navy- Clippings, 1938-1941., 1939-1941 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Communication in Poland- Front page of “Nowy Swiat”, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Commerce in Poland- Polish trade handwritten charts/notes., 1926-1937 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Cities in Poland- Handwritten notes; articles, 1938-1939. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - TWM- Pulaski Day speeches., 1964-1983 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - TWM- Various speeches at events, 1965-1984 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - TWM- Miscellaneous speeches & notes., 1964-1982 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Polish Air Force., 1970-1976 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Polish Art, 1975-1980 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Polish Calvary, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Nicolaus Copernicus, 1971-1973 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Polish Constitution Day, 1967-1976 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Joseph Conrad., 1972-1983 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Coins., 1974 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Eagle, 1967-1977 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Easter, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Education- Schools & colleges, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Flowers, 1970-1980 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Folk dancing & arts, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Gdansk, town at the Baltic sea., 1970-1980 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Gorals (mountaineers), 1970-1980 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Ancient Oath of Polish Trumpeteer, 1970-1980 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - History of Poland, 1966-1979 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Krakow & Jagiellonian University, 1965-1978 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Jamestown, Virginia, 1958-1976 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Jewish life in Poland, 1970-1981 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Music, 1976-1983 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - WWI Military history, 1973-1975 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - General military history, 1938 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Military after WWII, 1970-1979 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Museums & Castles, 1972-1973 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Katyn massacre, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Monarchy, 1975-1982 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Kosciuszko Foundation, 1975-1976 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Ancient laws, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Polish literature, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Witold Lutosławski, 1970-1980 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Lwów, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Jan Matejko, 1970-1980 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Adam Mickiewicz, 1974-1980 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Czeslaw Miłosz, 1980-1981 (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Military history (1772-1914), 1972-1984 (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Military history (Napoleon period), 1978-1984 (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Military history, 1831 & 1863 uprisings, 1970-1980 (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - Polish American history, 1968-1980 (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - Nationality, origins, character of Poles, etc., 1977-1984 (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - Navy, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - Opera, 1970-1980 (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - Ignacy Jan Paderewski, 1971-1975 (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - Philosophy, 1970-1980 (Box 12, Folder 43)
  - Poles in America, 1941-1984 (Box 12, Folder 44)
  - PAL- 300 Sobieski Anniversary, 1978-1983 (Box 12, Folder 45)
  - Religion, 1980-1981 (Box 12, Folder 46)
  - Rogalin, 1970-1980 (Box 12, Folder 47)
  - Science & scientific achievements, 1977-1984 (Box 12, Folder 48)
  - Henryk Sienkiewicz, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 49)
  - Polish customs and traditions, 1969-1980 (Box 12, Folder 50)
  - Polish glass, 1970-1980 (Box 12, Folder 51)
  - Pope John Paul II, 1979-1984 (Box 12, Folder 52)
  - Poznan, 1970-1980 (Box 12, Folder 53)
  - Battle of Raclawice, 1975-1976 (Box 12, Folder 54)
  - Mikolaj Rej (1505-1569), 1983 (Bin 12, Folder 55)
  - Tourist attractions, 1970-1985 (Box 12, Folder 56)
  - King John III Sobieski, 1968-1981 (Box 12, Folder 57)
  - Artur Szuk, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 58)
  - Tatars, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 59)
  - Stanislaw Wyspianski, 1974-1976 (Box 12, Folder 60)
  - Wilno, 1970-1980 (Box 12, Folder 61)
  - Wieliczka salt mine, 1970-1980 (Box 12, Folder 62)
  - Wawel Castle, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 63)
  - Warsaw, 1973-1983 (Box 12, Folder 64)
  - Warna, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 65)
  - Toruń, 1970-1980 (Box 12, Folder 66)
  - Lech Walesa, 1981-1984 (Box 12, Folder 67)
  - TWM- Correspondence and related material, 2000-2003 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - List of items donated to CPAA by TWM, 1987-2003 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence with Colonel Kajencki, 1995-2002 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Defamation material- Correspondence, clippings, 1987-1993 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - TWM anti-defamation cases and related material, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - TWM anti-defamation issues, 1995-2000 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Anti-defamation case involving “Military History” magazine and related correspondence, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Polish-American Guardian Society- Cases, correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - TWM membership in Polish Genealogical Society- Conferences, family history information, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Anti-Defamation case against Viking Princess Cruise, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - TWM anti-defamation- Cases and correspondence, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - TWM anti-defamation- Campaign on “Polish death camps” in The Palm Beach Post, 1986;1987;1990;1992 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - TWM involvement in anti-defamation cases, 1980’s, 1980-1989 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - TWM anti-defamation- Campaign against an editorial on Lech Walesa in the Palm Beach Post, 1989-1990 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - TWM anti-defamation actions, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - “A newspaper libel of our Polish heritage: A Case History how to Successfully Defend our Polish Heritage”, essay by TWM, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Monte Casino controversy- Article in the American Legion magazine, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - “Anti-defamation guide” pamphlet published by PAC Anti-Defamation Commission, 1980-1989 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - PAC Anti-Defamation Committee- Correspondence, 1980-1983 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - TWM anti-defamation issues, 1978-1979 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - “The Polish Joke syndrome” pamphlet by Don F. Kovalic, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - PAC – Correspondence, clippings, announcements, 1984-1987 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - PAC anti-defamation material, 1970-1978 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - TWM- PAC Civic Alertness Commission, 1970; 1982; 1984 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - PAC anti-defamation material– correspondence, resolutions, clippings, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - PAC Convention- Related correspondence, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - TWM- Aloysius Mazewski correspondence, 1978-1984 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - TWM retirement papers, 1984-1985 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - PAC Holocaust material- Articles, pamphlets, correspondence, reports, 1979-1984 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - TWM miscellaneous correspondence, 1964-2001 (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Governor’s Resolution Commemorating Polish Constitution Day, May 3, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - TWM papers- Material related to Maliszewski home in Windsor, CT that was featured in the movie “Parrish”- Photographs, clippings, letters, movie script, 1960-1961 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - TWM papers- Crazy Horse and Ziolkowski- Clippings, brochures, 1996-2002 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - TWM papers- Various articles and pamphlets related to Polonia issues, 1999-2002 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - TWM papers- Real estate- mortgage note (TMH Hotels, Inc.), 1983-1986 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - TWM papers- Real estate deeds- property on Mountain Road, Windsor, CT, 1950-1970 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - TWM papers- Real estate transactions, 1954-1956 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - TWM papers- Real estate transaction, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - TWM papers- Real estate- zoning application for land in Windsor, CT, 1983-1984 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - TWM papers- Real estate-zoning appeal for property in Windsor, CT, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - TWM papers- Real estate- zoning application for property at Mountain Road, Windsor, CT, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - TWM papers- Real estate transaction- Property at Bradford Drive, Windsor, CT, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - TWM papers- Real estate transaction- Property at Wells Street, Hartford, CT, 1950-1970 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - TWM papers- Real estate transaction- Property in Hartford, CT, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - TWM papers- Real estate transaction- Property at Rickie Road, New Hartford, CT, 1979-1980 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - TWM papers- Real estate transaction- Property at Bloomfield Avenue, Windsor, CT, 1968-1969 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - TWM papers- Property issue- Dunfey Lane, Windsor, CT, 1969-1970 (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - TWM papers- Real estate transaction- Property on Laurel Lane, Barkhamsted, 1980-1989 (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - TWM papers- Real estate- Bloomfield Avenue, Windsor, CT, 1956 (Box 16, Folder 28)
- Polish Legion of American Veterans (PLAV)
  - PLAV - Constitution and by-laws, 1947; 1949; 1953 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - PLAV – “Ritual and Manual”, 1939-1947 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - PLAV - 9th National Convention, Syracuse, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - PLAV - 10th National Convention, Akron, Ohio, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - PLAV - 11th National Convention, Boston, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - PLAV - 12th National Convention, Buffalo, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - PLAV - 14th National Convention, Hartford, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - PLAV - National Executive Committee Meeting - minutes [incomplete], 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - PLAV - Zone 1 reports, 1952-1954 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - PLAV- TWM, vice-commander, Zone 1 correspondence, 1952-1954 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - PLAV- TWM expense account, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - PLAV - forms, flyers, 1948-1955 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - PLAV- News release, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - PLAV - National News [scattered] see periodical collection, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - PLAV News [scattered] see periodical collection, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - The National PLAV news vol.1, no.1 1957, vol.20, no.2, 1977, 1957; 1977 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - PLAV, CT- Constitution, rules and regulations, parade etiquette, miscellaneous documents, 1947-1953 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - PLAV, CT- Minutes of monthly meetings [scattered], 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - PLAV, CT- 6th Annual Convention, Dept. Of Conn., Bristol, CT minutes, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - PLAV, CT- 7th Annual Convention, Norwich minutes, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - PLAV, CT- 8th Annual State Convention, Meriden, 1953; 9th Annual State Convention, Waterbury, 1954., 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - PLAV, CT- Merit awards for A. Sadlek & B. Truskowski, correspondence, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Program for Capt. Edmund P. Zbikowski Post No. 2 PLAV Post Dedication April 21-24,1954, Bristol, CT. (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - PLAV, CT - POST 51, Hartford: Constitution, Events, TWM resignation letter, Proposed changes in laws, 10th Anniversary pamphlet., 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - PLAVIAN- Post 51 part 1: 1950-52; 1948-vol. 2 no. 9. For holdings see Periodical collection., 1948-1952 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - PLAVIAN- Post 51 part 2: 1953-1957. (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - PLAV- Post 51 testimonial dinner for W. Lach, T. Maliszewski, W. Galuszka, H. Ramenda, 1955. (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Polish American Veterans of Massachusetts - 4th Annual State Convention, Springfield, 1952; 5th Annual State Convention, Gardner, 1953., 1952-1953 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Polish Veterans' Organizations in Massachusetts- Correspondence, clippings, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - The PLAV Bulletin - Wisconsin State Department, January- June, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - PLAV- Recruitment activities among veterans independent posts, 1948-1955 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - PLAV- Silver Jubilee, George Washington Post 3, Brooklyn, N.Y., 1953 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - PLAV Material- Newspaper clippings from Polish and English newspapers from Connecticut, Massachusetts, and New Jersey, 1948-1954 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - PLAV– Correspondence, 1952-1955 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - PLAV– Brochures, pamphlets, 1993-1995 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - PLAV Florida– 9th State Convention minutes, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - PLAV Florida– Constitution and by-laws, 1991-1995 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - PLAV Florida– Correspondence, minutes, resolutions, 1992-1996 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - PLAV Florida– State Convention, Lake Worth, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - PLAV Florida– Correspondence, minutes, 1996-1999 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Polish American Congress (PAC)
  - TWM - Polonia Distinguished Service Award, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Paderewski Cultural Association of Hartford- Constitution; creation of Polish library, 1954-1955 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Pulaski Day Parade- Hartford, 1956-1958 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Connecticut Civil War Centennial Commission, 1963-1965; American Polish Civil War Centennial Committee, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Polish University Club- Members, correspondence, 1966; 1976; 1980 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Polish Military History Society of America- Correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - National Advocate Society 1978-1980; list of Polish American lawyers in Connecticut, 1978. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Mikolaj Kopernik Foundation of New Britain, Connecticut, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Pulaski Day Observance - experts from speeches of Antoni Sadlak, 1950 [offprint from Congregational Record] (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - America's Immigration Curtain - remarks of Sen. William Benton [offprint from Congregational Record], 1951-1952 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Polish-American Democratic Club, Hartford- Constitution, membership list, correspondence., 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Pulaski Federation of Democratic Clubs of Connecticut- Constitution, clippings, miscellaneous correspondence., 1970-1988 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - SS. Cyril and Methodius Church Parish Council- Minutes, by-laws, correspondence, 1974-1984 (Box 4, Folder 13)